reiwa.com.au 2019-05-03

# REIWA's Privacy Policy And Internet Collection Notice - reiwa.com

## Privacy Policy

 _Last updated: May 2018  _

1\. REIWA is committed to complying with its obligations under the Privacy Act, 1988 and the associated Australian Privacy Principles (APPs). 

###  Application of the APPs to REIWA

2\. REIWA is bound by the APPs as a consequence of being an organisation with an annual turnover of more than three million dollars and due to the fact that it derives a benefit, service or advantage by the collection or disclosure of information and opinions about individuals whose identity is apparent or can be ascertained. 

3\. REIWA will not collect personal information unless it is reasonably necessary for, or directly related to, one or more of its functions or activities. 

4\. REIWA's designated Privacy Officer is: 

  * Name: Craig Bradley 
  * Email: [craig.bradley@reiwa.com.au](mailto:craig.bradley@reiwa.com.au?Subject=REIWA%20Privacy "craig.bradley@reiwa.com.au")
  * Telephone: (08) 9380 8222

5\. REIWA, through its Privacy Officer, is happy to provide further details as to the extent to which it is required to comply with the APPs should any person wish. Alternatively, further details of the obligations imposed upon organisations under Australia’s privacy laws can be obtained directly from the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner (Commissioner) or by reference to the APPs and the Commissioner’s associated guidelines at [oaic.gov.au](http://www.oaic.gov.au/ "Office of the Australian Information Comissioner"). 

### The types of information held by REIWA

6\. The type of personal information held by REIWA includes the following: 

  * names, email addresses, other contact details, residential and business mail addresses, the content of correspondence with REIWA (including emails, facsimiles and postal mail), gender information, occupation details, nature of any enquiry details details of properties and other personal information provided to REIWA by individuals, REIWA’s members, or REIWA’s service providers in acquiring, using or subscribing to REIWA’s services;

  * financial information such as information provided when applying for REIWA services and credit arrangements including, but not limited to, credit card/banking details; 

  * information collected by REIWA from visitors to its internet sites including, but not limited to, information provided when registering to use that website and details provided as part of any competitions or surveys conducted by REIWA. 

  * databases of sales, values, rentals and features of properties and/or businesses (including, but not limited to photographs and video images) constructed or maintained as part of the past, present or future provision of the services of reiwa.com; 

  * photographic identification of its members; 

  * details of the behaviour of users on REIWA’s internet sites including, but not limited to, information on reiwa.com accessed by users (including, but not limited to, details of properties and other content displayed on reiwa.com) IP addresses (not server addresses), previous sites visited, type of browsers used, nature of electronic devices used, internet pages accessed, cookies and location information; 

  * information collected by REIWA from REIWA social media sites including, but not limited to, Facebook, Twitter and LinkedIn; 

  * information collected in relation to applications for REIWA membership, the continuation of membership of REIWA and/or the use of REIWA services; 

  * information collected from members of the public in connection with consumer enquiries relating to real estate matters, in connection with complaints and arbitrations relating to REIWA members and in connection with details relating to property transactions; 

  * information collected from members of the public in connection with consumer enquiries relating to real estate matters, in connection with complaints and arbitrations relating to REIWA members and in connection with details relating to property transactions; 

  * data relating to land sales, values of properties and leases obtained from third parties including, but not limited to, Landgate and members of REIWA who use REIWA’s services; 

  * information collected from persons attending REIWA conventions, seminars and functions; 

  * information collected from persons applying for or attending training courses conducted by REIWA, including via REIWA’s business, “REIWA Learning” 

### Ways in which REIWA collects personal information

7\. REIWA collects personal information: 

  * from individuals, real estate and business agents and representatives (eg lawyers, settlement agents, accountants, financial advisers, banks);

  * from users of REIWA’s services or, alternatively, from potential users of those services; 

  * from REIWA members who provide REIWA with information for the purposes of using reiwa.com and other services provided by REIWA, including information pertaining to properties and the buying, selling and leasing of those properties by individuals; 

  * through REIWA’s internet and social media sites; 

  * through publicly available information services (eg telephone white pages, internet records); 

  * when REIWA is required to collect the information by virtue of legal or regulatory requirements; 

  * when individuals participate in competitions or surveys conducted by REIWA including, but not limited to, surveys relating to the quality of REIWA’s services provided and surveys relating to real estate matters; 

  * from databases kept by third party providers of services to REIWA and/or its members including, but not limited to, Landgate; 

  * from organisations and individuals who use REIWA’s services; 

  * from persons attending REIWA conventions, seminars and functions; 

  * from persons applying for or attending training courses conducted by REIWA, including via REIWA’s business, “REIWA Learning”.

### The primary purpose for which REIWA holds information

8\. REIWA holds the information referred to above for the purpose of enabling it to conduct the services that it provides to its members and the public, to enable it to market the provision of those services and to enable it to conduct its business. 

In particular, REIWA holds information: 

  * to enable it to service the interests of its members and provide membership services;

  * to provide information and services to the public with respect to real estate and ancillary matters; 

  * to provide consumer protection and mediation/arbitration services and to facilitate disciplinary procedures relating to its members; 

  * to provide internet services and maintain REIWA’s internet and social media sites; 

  * to assist REIWA members in the valuing, selling and/or leasing of properties and/or businesses; 

  * to assist REIWA and its members with marketing the services of REIWA and its members; 

  * to enable REIWA to inform its members and the public of additional information or services supplied by REIWA and its members that may be of interest to them; 

  * to provide personal information to REIWA’s contractors, who provide REIWA with services to assist REIWA with conducting its business; 

  * to provide personal information (such as information relating to the sale, purchase and/or leasing of properties on reiwa.com) to users of the reiwa.com internet site for the marketing of properties and the provision of statistical data with respect to those properties; 

  * to provide personal information (such as information relating to the sale, purchase and/or leasing of properties) to third parties including, but not limited to, entities that provide web development and management services to real estate agents, data collection agencies such as RP Data Pty Ltd and providers of services to the real estate industry; 

  * to enable REIWA and its third party contractors the ability to provide services to real estate agents based on data that contains details of information on reiwa.com accessed by users (including, but not limited to, details of properties and other content displayed on reiwa.com) so as to enable REIWA and its third party contractors to provide remarketing services to real estate agents (for example, to enable advertisements to appear on other web sites that are aimed at individual users based on information those users have previously accessed on reiwa.com); 

  * to enable REIWA to efficiently manage its business; 

  * to provide seminars, conventions and educational services to REIWA’s members and the public, including the services of REIWA’s business, “REIWA Training”; 

  * to enable REIWA to collate data for research and statistical purposes. 

  * to enable REIWA to comply with the statutory requirements of The Department of Training and Workforce Development (The Department) who ensure consistent and accurate capture and reporting of vocational education and training information about students. The National Centre for Vocational Education Research (NCVER) is the custodian for the collected information and may be accessed by officers of the Department and NCVER for the purpose of auditing participation and monitoring reporting of training outcomes. 

### Disclosure of personal information to overseas recipients

9\. REIWA discloses personal information to overseas recipients (eg data storage services), when that disclosure is consistent with the purpose(s) set out above. 

10\. The countries associated with the overseas recipients are, potentially, as follows: United States of America, Singapore and other Asian countries. 

### Right to gain access to personal information held by REIWA and its complaints handling processes

11\. Information that is stored by REIWA about an individual is stored in a reasonable state of security. 

12\. Pursuant to the APPs, persons have certain rights to obtain access to personal information held by REIWA with respect to that individual. Subject to the relevant exemptions contained in the APPs and subject to an individual providing sufficient proof of his or her identity, REIWA will provide access to information that it holds relating to an individual. REIWA reserves the right to charge a fee for the provision of this information based on the administrative cost of supplying the information requested. Further details as to these costs and the ability to access information held by us can be obtained by contacting REIWA’s Privacy Officer. 

13\. REIWA requests, for the purposes of clarity, that any requests for access to personal information be made in writing addressed to REIWA’s Privacy Officer. 

14\. REIWA will generally provide access to information by providing to the individual concerned copies of relevant documents. Where, for reasons of volume or otherwise, providing copies of documents is not practical, REIWA will make arrangements for the individual concerned to attend at its offices to carry out a physical inspection. 

15\. Wherever possible, REIWA will provide copies of documents or access to the information that it holds with respect to an individual within 14 days of the receipt of the relevant request. In the case of more complex requests REIWA will endeavour to provide access to the information within a period of 30 days. 

16\. If individuals believe that information held relating to them is incorrect they are entitled to request, by contacting REIWA’s Privacy Officer, that REIWA corrects that information. 

17\. Should REIWA believe that it is entitled to refuse a request to access information or to make corrections it will provide written reasons for that decision. 

18\. If an individual is dissatisfied with the manner in which REIWA deals with personal information or should an individual wish to make a compliant regarding REIWA’s compliance with privacy laws, please contact REIWA’s Privacy Officer in writing. 

### Further information

19\. Should any person wish to obtain further information with respect to the type of personal information REIWA holds, the purposes for which REIWA uses that information and/or the way in which REIWA manages that information, please contact REIWA’s Privacy Officer at the contact details set out above. 

### Changes to our Privacy Policy

20\. This document sets out REIWA’s current privacy policy. This policy will be reviewed from time to time and will be maintained in an up-to-date form. Any changes to this policy will be posted on the relevant section of REIWA’s website. 

## REIWA collection notice for use on its internet site

(AUSTRALIAN PRIVACY PRINCIPLES COLLECTION NOTICE) 

_Last updated: May 2018  _

1\. The notice is provided to you pursuant to the obligations placed upon REIWA and other organisations by the Privacy Act, 1988, and the associated Australian Privacy Principles (APPs). 

2\. It is important that readers of this statement note that REIWA may change its collection notices from time to time as part of our commitment to ensuring that it complies with all of its obligations under the APPs. Persons who access this REIWA internet site are urged to check to see whether we have amended our collection notices by returning to this site from time to time. To assist in this process, the date of the last update to this collection notice is recorded at the top of this statement. 

### The fact and circumstances of information collection

3\. REIWA collects information in the following circumstances: 

  * from individuals, real estate and business agents and representatives (eg lawyers, settlement agents, accountants, financial advisers, banks);

  * from REIWA members who provide REIWA with information for the purposes of using reiwa.com and other services provided by REIWA, including information pertaining to properties and the buying, selling and leasing of those properties by individuals; 

  * from users of REIWA’s services or, alternatively, from potential users of those services including, but not limited to, data from persons who access the reiwa.com website; 

  * through REIWA’s internet and social media sites; 

  * through publicly available information services (eg telephone white pages, internet records); 

  * when REIWA is required to collect the information by virtue of legal or regulatory requirements; 

  * when individuals participate in competitions or surveys conducted by REIWA including, but not limited to, surveys relating to the quality of REIWA’s services provided and surveys relating to real estate matters; 

  * from databases kept by third party providers of services to REIWA and/or its members including, but not limited to, Landgate; 

  * from organisations and individuals who use REIWA’s services; 

  * from persons attending REIWA conventions, seminars and functions; 

  * from persons applying for or attending training courses conducted by REIWA, including via REIWA’s business, “REIWA Training”. 

### Legal requirements to collect information

4\. REIWA may, from time to time, be required to collect information as a consequence of legal requirements upon it to collect information. Examples of these requirements include information that REIWA is obliged to collect under the _Associations Incorporation Act, 2015._

5\. Further information regarding these obligations can be obtained by contacting our Privacy Officer at the details set out below. 

### Purposes for which information collected

6\. REIWA collects information on its internet site and elsewhere for the following purposes: 

  * to enable it to service the interests of its members and provide membership services; 

  * to provide information and services to the public with respect to real estate and ancillary matters; 

  * to provide consumer protection and mediation/arbitration services and to facilitate disciplinary procedures relating to its members; 

  * to provide internet services and maintain REIWA’s internet and social media sites; 

  * to assist REIWA members and the public in the valuing, selling and/or leasing of properties and/or businesses; 

  * to assist REIWA and its members with marketing the services of REIWA and its members; 

  * to enable REIWA to inform its members and the public of additional information or services supplied by REIWA and its members that may be of interest to them; 

  * to provide personal information to REIWA’s contractors, who provide REIWA with services that assist REIWA with conducting its business; 

  * to provide personal information to third party providers of services to the real estate industry; 

  * to enable REIWA to efficiently manage its business; 

  * to provide seminars, conventions and educational services to REIWA’s members and the public, including via REIWA’s business, “REIWA Training”; 

  * to enable REIWA to collate data for research and statistical purposes; 

  * to provide personal information (such as information relating to the sale and/or leasing of properties on reiwa.com) to users of the reiwa.com internet site for the marketing of properties and the provision of statistical data with respect to those properties; 

  * to provide personal information (such as information relating to the sale, purchase and/or leasing of properties) to third parties including, but not limited to, entities that provide web site development and management services to real estate agents, data collection agencies such as RP Data Pty Ltd, and providers of services to the real estate industry; 

  * to enable REIWA and its third party contractors the ability to provide services to real estate agents based on data that contains details of information on reiwa.com accessed by users (including, but not limited to, details of properties and other content displayed on reiwa.com) so as to enable REIWA and its third party contractors to provide remarketing services to real estate agents (for example, to enable advertisements to appear on other web sites that are aimed at individual users based on information those users have previously accessed on reiwa.com); 

  * to enable REIWA to comply with the statutory requirements of The Department of Training and Workforce Development (The Department) who ensure consistent and accurate capture and reporting of vocational education and training information about students. The National Centre for Vocational Education Research (NCVER) is the custodian for the collected information and may be accessed by officers of the Department and NCVER for the purpose of auditing participation and monitoring reporting of training outcomes. 

### Consequences to an individual if information not provided

7\. Should a person object to REIWA collecting information about that individual via its website or otherwise, REIWA may not be able to provide its services as effectively, or at all, to that person. Further details may be obtained regarding these consequences by contacting our Privacy Officer at the details set out below. 

### Disclosure of personal information

8\. REIWA may disclose personal information in the following circumstances: 

  * REIWA provides personal information to its contractors, who provide REIWA with services to assist it with conducting its business; 

  * REIWA may store information on data storage facilities provided by third parties; 

  * REIWA may use/disclose information relating to the sale, purchase and/or leasing of properties by providing that information to data collection agencies such as RP Data Pty Ltd; 

  * REIWA may disclose to its third party contractors information so as to provide services to real estate agents based on data that contains details of information on reiwa.com accessed by users (including, but not limited to, details of properties and other content displayed on reiwa.com) so as to enable REIWA and its third party contractors to provide remarketing services to real estate agents (for example, to enable advertisements to appear on other web sites that are aimed at individual users based on information those users have previously accessed on reiwa.com);

### REIWA’s Privacy Policy

9\. REIWA maintains a privacy policy in compliance with its obligations under APP 1. This privacy policy may be viewed on the REIWA website or a copy may be obtained by contacting our Privacy Officer at the details set out below. 

### Disclosure of personal information to overseas recipients 

10\. REIWA may disclose personal information to overseas recipients (eg data storage services), when that disclosure is consistent with the purposes set out above. 

11\. The countries associated with the overseas recipients are, potentially, as follows: United States of America, Singapore and other Asian countries. 

### Our contact details and Privacy Officer

12\. The contact details for REIWA are available from this website. The particular contact details for our Privacy Officer are as follows: 

  * Name: Craig Bradley 
  * Email: [craig.bradley@reiwa.com.au](mailto:craig.bradley@reiwa.com.au "craig.bradley@reiwa.com.au")
  * Telephone: +61 8 9380 8222 

### Cookies

13\. _“Cookies”_ are pieces of information that websites transfer to an individual computer’s hard drive for record keeping purposes. That “cookie” assigns a unique identification that allows a website to recognise you when you return to that site. 

14\. REIWA uses cookies so as to collect aggregated site-visitation statistics. The use of cookies also enables persons to login to their accounts with REIWA and to personalise their experience when browsing the REIWA site. This enables REIWA to ensure that it manages its website effectively so as to provide relevant content to those who access the site. REIWA does not track an individual’s use of the internet by using cookies and does not otherwise use these tools to obtain personally identifiable information regarding an individual. 

15\. Most internet browsers enable individuals to refuse to accept cookies. If an individual exercises such a choice you will still be able view most of the text on this internet site. However, you will not experience a personalised visit. 

### IP Addresses

16\. Whenever you use the REIWA website, and many other websites, the computer on which the web pages are stored (the web server) needs to know the network address of your computer so that it can send the requested web pages to your internet browser. The unique network address of your computer is called its “IP address” and is sent automatically each time you access any internet site. From a computer’s IP address, it is possible to determine the general geographic location of that computer, but otherwise it is anonymous. 

17\. REIWA does not keep a record of the IP addresses from which users access its site except where the user has specifically provided it with information about itself, in which case REIWA also records the user’s IP address for security purposes. 

### Right to gain access to information and complaints handling processes

18\. Any information that is stored by REIWA about an individual is stored in a reasonable state of security. Individuals have certain rights under the APPs to access information stored by an organisation about them. 

19\. Should a person wish to contact REIWA to gain access to the details of the information stored by it regarding that individual, that person should make contact with REIWA’s Privacy Officer. Subject to legal obligations upon REIWA, including REIWA’s rights and obligations under the _Privacy Act, 1988,_ REIWA will provide that access. REIWA reserves the right to make a reasonable charge to cover its costs for granting that access. 

20\. Should a person wish to make a complaint about the manner in which REIWA has dealt with any privacy issue, that person should make contact with the REIWA Privacy Officer. 

21\. Further details regarding access to information and REIWA’s complaints handling process are set out in REIWA’s Privacy Policy or can be obtained by contacting the REIWA Privacy Officer at the details set out above. 

### Queries regarding privacy

22\. Any queries that the reader of this document may have about REIWA’s privacy compliance should be directed to the REIWA Privacy Officer at the details set out above. 

### REIWA eFlyers

From March 2013, real estate agents may send you 'REIWA eFlyers'. You should never receive more than one of these a day and you can unsubscribe from these independently of your subscription to REIWA alerts, saved and watching properties. 

REIWA Information Service Privacy Statement 

_Last updated: 19 September 2003_

58\. When persons contact REIWA or use one of its services by telephone, REIWA will frequently take a record regarding the nature of the person's enquiry, including the person's name, a summary of the content of the enquiry and, in certain circumstances, the person's address and/or telephone number. The person can later access this information to check its correctness should he/she wish. 

59\. REIWA records this information for administrative purposes so as to keep a record of enquiries made to it. On occasions this information may be passed on to organisations associated with these purposes. 

60\. Should an individual not wish REIWA to record his/her personal information, it will frequently not be possible for REIWA to deliver the service the individual is seeking to access. 

### Reproduction Consent

If you would like to request consent from the copyright holder of this website, REIWA, to reproduce or copy sections of reiwa.com's content, email Privacy Officer Craig Bradley at [craig.bradley@reiwa.com.au](mailto:craig.bradley@reiwa.com.au "craig.bradley@reiwa.com.au").
